<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="asynchelp">AsyncTaskScreen Help</string>
    <string name="asynchelptext">        
        This is an example of using AsyncTask.  AsyncTask should be used when you are expecting a long running task, 
        or any time a long running task should occur.  AsyncTask creates a separate thread, which runs in doInBackground().  Making HTTP calls 
        from within the main UI thread is bad practice.
        \n\n
        In this particular example, I am randomly sleeping for a certain number of intervals.  After each interval, the progress bar is updated.  
        The total time in seconds represents the total amount of sleep time.	</string>
    <string name="oscodehelptext">        
        OpenSourceCodeSamplesRon is an open source collection of various samples of the Android API.  Hopefully, you will find some useful 
        information to help with your own project.
        \n\n
        Help screens on subsequent pages have been added as menu items.  This is to visually keep the focus on the sample.  Help screens can be 
        accessed from the Android device\'s menu option button.  The help screens are meant to give some general ideas and mention some of the 
        technologies involved in the sample.  For each sample I have tried to create a help screen.  Each of those help screens are also 
        accessible via a menu from the main page titled Sample Code.
        \n\n
        Having been a Java JEE developer for nearly 10 of my 15 years at a fortune 500 company and a programmer for nearly 17
		years, I decided to move toward creating Android applications. The move has been enjoyable, challenging and eye-opening as to its
		potential. I recently created Golf Card Keeper application, which is available on Android Market.  
		\n\n
		My email address is androidron1@hotmail.com, which I will occasionally check.  Any feedback would be appreciated.  
		\n\n
		Thanks, 
		\n
		Ron Currier	</string>
    <string name="spinnerhelp">Spinner Sample Help</string>
    <string name="spinnerhelptext">
        Choosing a color from the first spinner causes the background color to change to that choice.  Similarly, 
        choosing a color from the second causes the text color to change.
        \n\n
        Although it is a fairly rudimentary example, it shows the usage of Spinners, ArrayAdapters, populating from 
        an array, and setting colors by getting resources.
    </string>
    <string name="cpsampleshelp">Content Provider Samples Help</string>
    <string name="cpsampleshelptext">
        Content Provider Samples gives examples of creating and using 2 content providers.  Per the developer guide for Content Providers, 
        http://developer.android.com/guide/topics/providers/content-providers.html:  "Content providers store and retrieve data and make 
        it accessible to all applications. They're the only way to share data across applications; there's no common storage area that all 
        Android packages can access."  "If you want to make your own data public, you have two options: You can create your own content 
        provider (a ContentProvider subclass) or you can add the data to an existing provider — if there's one that controls the same type 
        of data and you have permission to write to it." 
        \n\n
        In addition to creating the content providers, there are examples of inserting, deleting and accessing the data.  Other interesting 
        items of note are passing extras from one activity to another, using a SimpleCursorAdapter, using Toasts, and creating 
        Data Access Objects (DAOs).
    </string>
    <string name="thumbnailhelp">Thumbnail Sample Help</string>
    <string name="thumbnailhelptext">
        Thumbnail Sample displays a variety of tumbnails at the bottom of the page in a Gallery.  Clicking on one of the pictures gives a 
        larger version in the ImageView.  Since LayoutParams takes pixels as parameters, there is a converter to convert from DP to pixels.
    </string>
    <string name="dtphelp">DateTimePicker Help</string>
    <string name="dtphelptext">
        DateTimePicker is an example of using Date and Time Picker Dialogs.  For the DatePicker Dialogs, I have checked to see if they are 
        Honeycomb/post-Honeycomb or pre-Honeycomb.  If post-Honeycomb, use setCalendarViewShown(true) on the DatePicker instance for DatePickerDialog, as 
        setCalendarViewShown() existed since Honeycomb, sdk version 11.
        \n\n
        Additionally, there are examples of using onSaveInstanceState() and onRestoreInstanceState() for setting and for restoring instance 
        state information.
    </string>
    <string name="notificationhelp">Notification Help</string>
    <string name="notificationhelptext">
        The Notification Activity gives an example of using a system service.  In this case, we are creating a Notification to use in the 
        NotificationManager.  There is a tickerText, showing on the display for a short time, similar to a Toast.  And, there is a small 
        notification icon showing the most recent notification when clicked.  Both the tickerText and the latest event text are user input.
    </string>
    <string name="websamplehelp">WebSample Help</string>
    <string name="websamplehelptext">
        Web Sample gives an example of using an Alert Dialog in addition to accessing the internet via 2 browser types, an internal browser, 
        and a full external browser.  Clicking the Reset button will bring the dialog back up.
    </string>
    <string name="intentservicehelp">Intent Service Sample Help</string>
    <string name="intentservicehelptext">This example incorporates several important concepts I\'d like to discuss in further detail:  Services, IntentServices, BroadcastReceivers,
        AlarmManagers and Notifications.  It is a bit contrived since AlarmManagers do not take very long to set up and can therefore be run on the main UI thread.
        Services are used to allow background/ long running processes to occur or to supply functionality for other applications to use.  Services can be either Remote, accessible by other applications on the 
        device, or Local, only accessible by the creating application.  This is an example of using a local service.  Local services are started calling Context.startService() and continues
        until Context.stopService() is called OR the service itself calls stopSelf().  There is a limited amount of time before the user receives a ANR,
        Application Not Responding, message. Five seconds in the UI and ten seconds for BroadcastReceiver.  Services do NOT run in a separate thread.  Therefore, new threads are needed
        to avoid interfering with the main thread for long running services.  This can be solved by creating a Thread in the Service and doing business logic in the new thread.  Or, 
        you could use Handlers to interact with the thread.
        \n\n
        Service/IntentService - IntentService is a Service class that uses a Handlers and creates a separate thread.  Method onHandleIntent(Intent intent) needs to be over-ridden.  This is where the business logic would go.  
        There are a couple of key differences between IntentService and Service.  Normally in Services, you would over-ride onBind() (which would then return null in the case of a local service).  IntentService already returns null from
        onBind(), so there is no need to over-ride.  Additionally, if there are no outstanding messages queued for the handler, IntentService will call stopSelf(), which calls the onDestroy() method and stops the service.
        This can affect the design.  The code to cancel the initial notification, create the secondary notification and cancel the alarm
        were done in the activity because I wanted the user to be able to execute these functions.  Otherwise, they would happen so quickly in this case, the user may not see certain aspects of
        what is occurring.
        \n\n
        BroadcastReceiver - Both BroadcastReceiver and Service (IntentService) must be registered in the Android Manifest.  BroadcastReceivers respond to 
        some service or activity broadcasting an intent using the Context.sendBroadcast() method.  BroadcastReceivers extend Receiver and are registered as 
        using the receiver tag in the manifest.  As with other intents, the broadcast intent can contain an extra.
        \n\n
        AlarmManagers - AlarmManager is a system service provided on Android devices.  With it, you can schedule events to occur, either once or repeatedly.  
        This example creates an AlarmManager to access a BroadcastReceiver.  This is done through a PendingIntent.  PendingIntent.getBroadcast() acts as 
        Context.sendBroadcast() when executed through the AlarmManager.
        \n\n
        Notifications - This is another example of using notifications.  The notification initial created in the service sets a flag to Notification.FLAG_NO_CLEAR.
        This flag prevents the notification from being canceled when the user clicks the Clear all button.  The PendingIntent points to the activity, allowing the 
        user to get back to the activity by clicking on the notification, such as from the home screen.
        Also reference the help from the Notification screen.  Note:  As of Android API 11, the constructor used is 
        deprecated.  The reference says to use Notification.Builder instead.	</string>
    <string name="ttssamplehelp">TTS Sample Help</string>
    <string name="ttshelptext">
        With this application, you can enter text and the application will speak it as in US English.  TTS (Text To Speech) uses the Pico Engine that comes with Android.  
        TTS has been around since Android API 4.  Due to device constraints, related resources are not always fully installed for TTS.  Therefore, you should first check 
        whether or not the device is resource ready for TTS.  This is done by calling startActivityForResult() and checking the result in onActivityResult().  If
        the resources are not installed, call the intent to allow the resources to be installed.
        \n\n
        The spoken language/accent is set via setLanguage().  There is a variety of languages and locales that can be used.  The specifics of which ones can be investigated 
        should you need to choose another.  The pitch is set via setpitch(), which defaults to 1.0f.  Using a smaller pitch makes the voice deeper, larger values make it 
        higher.  In speak(), there is a parameter called QUEUE_FLUSH.  This will flush the queue, dropping any other speech for the application already in the TTS speech queue.	</string>

</resources>